Guide to the John Tabor Kempe Papers 1678-1782 (bulk 1752-1774) MS 344
New-York Historical Society
- Series 1: Court Case Records, 1678-1778 (bulk 1752-1774), and Undated, 1678-1778 and Undated
  - Subseries 5: Undetermined Courts
    - Henry Hartley vs. George Harrion, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - [Anthony Hausch, Johan Driksler, John Caub, Johannis Heberlein, John Seidell, Johan Becker, Anna Hartmannin, Regina Baurin, Anthony Becker, Johan Rudolph, Susanna Rudolph, Nicholas Bethman, Anna Margaritta] aka "the Germans" vs. Richard Tole [Toll] and Captain Pinkerman [Pikeman]: Extortion, 1754 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Case involves German immigrants on the ship Amelia. The case complains that the defendents were charged more money than they agreed upon when they arrived in New York. Case includes peitition and accounts.
    - William Hendrick vs. James Curtice, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Hodgson vs. Lewis Pintard, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Anthony Hoffman [Hofman] vs. Jacob Ten Broeck: Debt, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Ulster County; See letter from Anthony Hoffman to Philip Livingston, dated September 9, 1767.
    - Hezekia Holdridge vs. Solomon Purdy et al., 1758 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      See letter from Ebenezor Kniffin to William Kempe, dated March 2, 1758. Petitions of defendants describing Holdridge's "wicked practices."
    - Sarah Hudnut [Hudnuts] vs. Edward Blower: Trespass and other damages, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Charged with false promises of marriage. See also: letter from John Tabor Kempe to Ringo, dated March 19, 1772; Letter from Sarah Hudnut to John Tabor Kempe, dated April 15, 1772; and John Tabor Kempe to Edward Blower, dated November 16, 1772.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Trustees of Kingston vs. William Dederick: Ejectment, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Case includes trial notes.
    - James Johnson vs. Timothy Smith, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Depositions of Sarah Deusenbere and Martha Smith.
    - [Robert Shert ex dem] Hercules Janse Krankhirt and Jacobus Krankhy vs. Jacob Lent, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mathias Lapert vs. Gabriel Legget: Assault, 1758 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Kings County
    - Margaret Linnerd vs. John Dowers and Deborah Bealley: Assault, 1752 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Eneas MacIntosh vs. Alexander Ross: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - James Magra vs. William Brownjohn Jr., 1772 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - David Matthews vs. Donald Campbell, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Albany and Ulster Counties
    - Alexander McDonald vs. Alexander Vance, 1769-1770 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - John Morrel vs. Richard Wood, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Isaac Moses vs. Andrew Seton: Debt, 1775 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Robert and John Murray vs. Rem Rapalje and Peter Mesier: Trespass, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Adolph Myer vs. Jacobus Myer, 1771 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      See letter from Isaac Browne to John Tabor Kempe, dated March 31, 1773.
    - Joseph Myers and Justina Warnery vs. Captain Caldwell, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Nepthali Hart Myers vs. John Bradstreet: Debt, 1769-1772 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Financial dispute between John Bradstreet and Nepthali Hart Myers involving Mary Bradstreet's account. See correspondence from John Tabor Kempe to Bradstreet dated 20 August, 1771; 29 August, 1771; and 2 April, 1772 urging him to settle dispute without trial.
    - Isabella Neely, executor of Robert Neely vs. Jacobus Brown, executor of James McNeal, 1759-1760 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      See correspondence from John Tabor Kempe to Jacobus Brown, 18 March, 1760 and "Isble" Neely to Thomas Neely, 6 October, 1759. John Tabir Kempe writes to Brown that he hopes the case will be settled without a law suit and it is unclear if the case ever came to trial. Case includes petition, copy of will, statement of case, and notes.
    - James Phyn and Alexander Elice vs. John Duncan, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Jonas Phillips vs. John Carpenter: Slander, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Poyer vs. McIntosh, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      John Tabor Kempe requested to read this at his leisure.
    - Margaret Price vs. Cavalier Jouet [Janet], Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Appears to be a promise of marriage case.
    - Paul Richard vs. James Mills, 1752 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - John Riley vs. Arthur McNeil [McNiel]: Trespass, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Willet Seaman vs. Daniel Stiles, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Captain Sears vs. Joseph Totten, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - William Denning vs. Joseph Totten, 1773 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      On the same sheet as Sears vs. Totten.
    - Phillip Servent vs. Nathanel Baremore [Bearmore] [Baremor]: Debt, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      See also a letter from Phillip Servent to John Tabor Kempe dated October 28, 1762.
    - Jeremiah Short vs. Christopher Hondefort: Fraud, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Robert Sinclair vs. William Neilson, 1773-1774 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Case includes council fees.
    - Ann McVey vs. Captain Griffin, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      On the same sheet with John Williams vs. Captain Denney.
    - Joseph Smith and Philip Scheffier vs. George Cronkheight et al.: Riotous assembly, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Samuel Smith vs. Amos Mills: Trespass and debt, 1768-1772 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Garret Snedecker vs. Henry Guinard and Henry Halstead: Ejectment, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Alexander Solomon vs. William Williams, 1760 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Case on John Tabor Kempe's agenda, 1761.
    - Jeremiah Springsteen vs. William Davenport, 1770 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Dutchess County; Case on John Tabor Kempe's agenda, 1771.
    - John Sutton vs. Patrick Boyle, 1755 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - John David Wasner vs. Ledowick Bamper and Captain Thomas; Indentured servant case, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - John Wetherhead, adm vs. John Laboyteaux, 1775 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Regarding the estate of John Hodgson, deceased.
    - Isiah Wickson vs. Mophen Gates, 1759 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Neighbor's swear that Isiah Wickson's wife was abused by Mophen Gates.
    - Mary Wilkinson and Balthazar Woorsover vs. Archibald Campbell: Riot and assault, 1758 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - John Williams vs. Captain Denney, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      See also: Ann McVey vs. Captain Griffin on the same sheet.
    - Mary Wilson vs. John Campbell: Assault, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Opinion, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      John Tabor Kempe's opinion on Captain Farrel's bill of exchange.
  - Subseries 6: Undetermined Cases
    - Elizabeth Burger Complaint, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Elizabeth Burger complaint against Simmons, McCain, Campbell, and Jasper Corke for nonpayment of wine.
    - William Bowens and Dr. Thomas Wright Assault Case, 1766 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Note: Westchester County
    - Estate Case of Anna Dircks, 1678-1680 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Anna Dircks was the widow of Peter Cock. John Tabor Kempe's interest in case is unclear and most of the documents are in Dutch.
    - Case involving Francis Comono, 1753 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Case involving Francis Comono, an African indentured servant. The case includes a description of Comono's journey from Guinea to New York, an indenture (copy), affidavit, and complaint.
    - Assault Case of Abraham and Peter Fonda, 1764 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Statement of case was enclosed with a letter from Peter Silvester to John Tabor Kempe, dated February 24, 1764. Letter is now in correspondence.
    - Petition of John Dunn from jail, 1766 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Statement of debt case by William Dudley, 1766 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Mittimus, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Mittimus to convey Mary Atkins to bridewell, hard labour. See also letter to John Tabor Kempe from Mary Atkinson.
    - Ties Bont, William Rase, and Abraham Hallenbeck Notes of Evidence, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Defendants claim to have been unjustly fined by Henry Van Ranselaer while embployed by Cornelia Van Hoese.
    - Estate case of Samuel Burling, Edward Burling, and Thomas Dobson, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Will of Ann De Peyster, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Statement of Case against Cornelius Cuyler et al., 1762 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Trial in Kinderhook, NY. Statement of case against Cornelius Cuyler and others, 55th Regiment, indicted on complaint of John Van Ness; dispute over horses and carriages.
    - Case of Thomas Chahaen, 1769 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Deposition of John Hay [Hays], 1766 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Depositions regarding John Hay [Hays], accused of raping and assaulting nine-year-old Elizabeth Kidney. Deposition of Dr. James Smith, Elizabeth Kidney, Elizabeth Kidney, Sr., Edward Rodgers, and John Duly.
    - Report of examination against John Hanson, 1760 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Affidavit of Theunis Krom [Crom], 1764 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Orange County; Affidavit regarding a riot or larceny. Names include John Ecsersen, Jacob Strat, Gerrit Onderdunck, and John Patersen Smith.
    - Statement of Case, 1771 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      John Tabor Kempe's opinion of the case of John Hatton.
    - Assault case, 1758 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Assault case involving wife of George Licker and the wife of Abraham Rinere.
    - Note of recognizance, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Dutchess County; David Smith charged with stealing from Catherine Hordenbergh.
    - Deposition of Elizabeth Leonard re: Samuel Smith, larceny, 1764 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Case involving Icro, slave to Francis Peter Rogen [Roggen], 1765 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Deposition of Robert Rogers [Rodgers], 1766 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Deposition concerns brig Polly; Deposition of John Welch, mariner on the brig Polly, and filed under "Liberty Boys."
    - Case of Emanuel Joseph, mariner on Royal Charlotte, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Deposition of Elizabeth Johnson: Riot, 1765 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Petition of Ann Gordon, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Case in Albany County. Petition requestion attention to Gordon's assault case against Cornelius Van Schaack.
    - Affidavit of John Gough, 1762 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Affidavit of John Gough involving a letter he received addressed to John Tabor Kempe that was broken open before being delivered.
    - Information on Benjamin Gardner, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Trial in Albany County. Information regarding a dispute over land claims in Vermont territory.
    - Affidavit of Thomas Graves, 1768 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Affidavit regarding William Buchanan's larceny of fruit from Andrew Seton's orchard.
    - Account of Thomas Hautzman, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Thomas Hautzman's account of seizure of the sloop Sally and Ephraim Farnum, master.
    - Indenture of Francisco Gose, 1753 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      The indenture is for Fracisco Gose, a free black from Curacao.
    - Warrant for Thomas Minzey: Larceny, 1767 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - James McDaniel vs. Tuff Elsworth and George Tilsey, 1752 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum of John McNeal, 1774 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Regarding Archibald McCurdy.
    - Case Statement of Elias March, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Depositions, 1756 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Depositions of Elizabeth Extream, Isabella MacGinnis, and Michael Frederick regarding John McDaniel [MacDaniel] and stolen goods. Also included is The King vs. John McDaniel and Simon Kilroy for highway robbery, in Legal Executions, 1757.
    - Affidavit and Statement of Case, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Case involves Simon Moore, an African-American apprentice from North Carolina, charging Samuel Bayard with illegally keeping him as a slave in New York.
    - Case involving Joseph Mutts, 1757-1762 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Orange County; Case involving Johannes Mutts, dispute over will and property. See also: letter from John Tabor Kempe to William Felton and George Reims, October 15, 1769; letter from John Tabor Kempe to Nathaniel Boarmore, dated February 18, 1762.
    - John Tabor Kempe's opinion on Alexander McDonald's case, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Opinion regards the sale of MacDonald's effects by William Neilson. Cornelius Ryan also involved. Case includes memorial, account, opinion, and draft of agreement.
    - Notes on a controversy, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Controversy between the executors of Lewis Morris, the executors of James Wardriop, and the administration of Captain Robert Etherington. Case includes notes.
    - Power of attorney, 1755-1756 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Power of attorney involving Edward Murphy, Mary Murphy, and William Richards. Case includes letter of attorney, direction, and memo.
    - Warrant, 1761 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Dutchess County; Case against Peter Monfort and William Hogelandt involving stolen rails.
    - Riot Case, 1765 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Trial in Dutchess County. Riot case involving Henry Schoenmaker, minister of the Dutch Church at Poughkeepsie and Fishkill, Elias Van Bunschooten, Peter Van Kleeck, Aerdt Middagh, Boudevine De la Count, and Petrus Van Vleet. Alleges Schoenmaker was attacked at the pulpit.
    - List of rioters in Orange Town, 1767 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      List of rioters in Orange Town, March 21, 1767. Names include Jacob Sraat, Edward Philips, Johannes Mabie, Cornelius Blauvelt, Cornelius Smith, Peter Haring, Johannes Haring, Cornelius Haring, John de Baan, William Petersen, Isaac de Pue, and Johannes Blauvelt.
    - Property Dispute, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Dutchess County; Property Dispute involving John Oats Sr., John Oats, Jr., and Samuel Oats. See also a letter from William Humfrey [Humphreys] to William Kempe, dated September 12, 1754.
    - Complaint of Thomas Mulliners, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Complaint against Joseph Rodman, Samuel Rodman, George Crawford, Joshua Hunt, and Pell Sands involving an assault.
    - Warrant against Elbert Onderdenk [Onderdonk], 1763 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Affidavit of Captain James Thomas re: Sloop Jenny, 1772 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notes on property dispute, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Notes on a property dispute involving James Spencer, Andrew Emans, and Rebecca Emans.
    - Statement of case, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Case of Jacob Quaco, free man from Curacao, sold into slavery in Rhode Island.
    - Case involving property of Derrick Ten Eyck, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Financial papers of John Sant, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Case includes agreements and accounts.
    - Examination of Lambertus Van Grieter and deposition of Henry Stanton, 1756 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      These seem to discuss the same incident, a fray that involved the death of John Web. Filed under 'Stanton'.
    - Deposition of Robert Smith and Margaret Rodey, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Deposition regarding an attack by Catherine Boyce.
    - Deposition of Isaac Terbush, 1770 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Deposition of Isaac Terbush in regards to Jarcerah Jarudon, Matheau Brett, and Thomas Devenport [Davenport].
    - Complaint of Anthony Sargent, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Complaint against Charles Oliver Bruff for lottery fraud.
    - Names of witnesses against the two Indians in Goal, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Filed at end of folder. "Names of witnesses against thw two Indians in Goal." Witnesses: "James Gall a whiteman; Rufus Franks a Negro; Daniel Hastins a whiteman" May be relaResolution by the General Assembly of Rhode Island to return two Indians.
    - Note of evidence, 1763-1765 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Note of Cornelius Ten Brook, Johannes Van Valhenburgh, Adam Cook regarding Cornelius Van Hosen. See also "Situation of the proceeding of Henry Van Ranssalaer [Renssalaer] against a Number of persons at Claverack on a supposed Riot," case appears to be related.
    - Account of affair by Captain Wetterstroom, 1757 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Account regarding Brinckerhoff [Brinkerhoff] and an alleged slave, Peter Lamb, who joined Wetterstroom's company.
    - Land Dispute involving Samuel Powell, Sarah Powell, and John Wenham, 1774 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      See letter from John Robinson to John Tabor Kempe, date 3 March, 1774.
    - Draft of award, 1770 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Draft involves Godardus Van Solingen and Joseph Janney.
    - Indenture of Elizabeth Williamson, free black, to William Hardenbrook, 1751 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Deposition of John Walworth: Land dispute, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Albany County; Deposition in regards to James Brekinridge, William Henry, Elinater Hubbel, Simon Robertson, and Harris.
    - Warrant for John Wilson et al., 1774 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Alderman William Waddell's warrant for John Willson, John Wetherston, and Joseph Young, mariners on the ship Glasgow, who allegedly refused their duty. Complaint of Solomon Townsend.
    - John Tabor Kempe's notes on Recloff Vanderlinde's case, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Case pertains to the entitlement of a "Negro Wench."
    - Draft of award, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Dispute between Jacobus Van Zandt [Vanzandt] and Mary Miller, executor of Paul Miller.
    - Affidavit of Beekman Van Bueren, 1757 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Affidavit regards the death of a bastard child of John Ellis and Anne Annet. See also a letter from William Kempe to John Burnet dated April 22, 1757 [perhaps relating to the same case].
    - Affidavit of Isaac Verrian regarding a riot, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - John Tabor Kempe's opinion on will of Augustus Vallette, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Deed between Cornelius Webber and Cornelia Lent, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Estate dispute, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Trial in Ulster County. Dispute over the estate of William West involving his freeing of his slaves. The case involves John [Johannis] Wynkoop. Susan West, in a letter to John Tabor Kempe, states that William West freed his slaves [her parents] and their children upon his death and left them his estate.
    - Affidavits before JP of Westchester County, 1757 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Westchester County; Affidavits regarding William Weeks and John Jones, deserters from a New York regiment.
    - Henry Van Schaack's narrative, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Narrative of threats against Henry Van Schaak in Albany, 1766. Riotous crowds mistakingly thought Van Schaack had been named Distributor of Stamps.
    - Statement of Captain Ward's case for Captain Williams: Debt, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Appeal of John [Johannes] Vanderheyden: Rape and promise of marriage, 1754 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      John [Johannes] Vanderheyden's appeal to the grand jury on behalf of his daughter, Rachel, allegedly raped by James Wilson. Case also involves a promise of marriage. See also correspondence from Vanderheyden to William Kempe dated 12 June, 1754 and 3 July, 1754. Includes a rough draft from William Kempe. Case includes a statement of case, speech, and affidavit.
    - Resolution by the General Assembly, Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Filed at the end of folder. Resolution by the General Assembly of Rhode Island to return two Indians accused of murder in New York. May be related to "Names of Witnesses against thw two Indians in Goal" in Box 12, Folder 2.
    - Estate of William Pride [Pridie] [Pridey] [Pridde], Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Case includes estate papers and accounts.
    - Wills of Matthew Benson, Henry Smith, and David Devore, 1752-1770 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Petition on behalf of Abraham DeWitt, 1762 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Sussex and Orange Counties; DeWitt was in Orange County jail for the passing of counterfeit money.
    - Petition of Gloriana Ginderil [Ginderell], 1758 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition and complaint from Gloriana Ginderil to stop proceedings against her by Justice Bloomer.
    - Petition of Joseph Greswold, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      See also John Tabor Kempe to Joseph Greswodl, 4 June, 1771. Case includes petition.
    - Petition, 1760 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition of Cornelius Joyce, William Young, William James, James Aberdeen, and Barney Callaghan regarding the private sloop of war Little Bobb under the command of Captain John Hansen. Case involves the sloop cruising the Carribbean for enemies of war and charged with passing off cargo as war prizes.
    - Petition opposing dam of William Duane, 1770 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Case in Albany County. Petition opposes dam because it inhibits the rafting of logs. Filed under Bradshaw, the first name on the complaint.
    - Petition of Charles Gilmore, 1731 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Petition of Peter Van Zandt, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Petition of Simon Stevens, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition for land Simon Stevens is entitled to as a veteran of the French and Indian War.
    - Peition of Alexander [Alejandro] Joseph de la Torre and Antonio Tyayo [Tyalo] [Tialo], Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition of de la Torre and Tyayo, two free blacks, for release from jail. See correspondence from De la Torre and Tyayo to William Kempe, dated 7 November, 1753 and 9 November, 1753.
    - Petition of Vacan [Juaquin] Beneto, 1755 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition on behalf of Vacan [Juaquin] Beneto and his son, free men brought to New York on the ship King George and sold as slaves.
    - Petition of Captain George Gmelin, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Petition of John Young, 1770 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition claims false imprisonment. See also a letter from John Young to John Tabor Kempe, dated 29 January, 1770.
    - Petition of Elizabeth Yeates, 1760 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition on behalf of Elizabeth Yeates' husband, Thomas Yeates.
    - Petition of Committee and Freeholders of Tryon County, 1778 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition regarding the appointment of officers in the county and the distressed state of residents in Tryon County.
    - Petition of David McKendles and John Shaw, 1774 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition from debtor's prison for relief.
    - Petition of Thomas English against Judath Houper, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Petition of Augustus Bradley, 1760 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition of prisoner Augustus Bradley, accused of attempting to forge and defraud Nathaniel Marston, declaring his innocence. See also two letters to John Tabor Kempe from Bradley, correspondence.
    - Petition of Anny [Ann] Fowserey, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition of Anny Fowserey, an indentured servant complaining of ill treatment.
    - Petition of Katerien Corgall, 1768 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition to the mayor of Albany accusing Abraham Person with rape and charging local Justices of the Peace of inaction in the case.
    - Petition of Jacob Fry, Seth Sherwood, William Hartwell, Joseph Hopkins, Joseph Conklin, William Young, Hendrick Young, and Hendrick Smith, 1771 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition regarding the poor condition in debtor's jail.
    - Petition of John Constable, 1765 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Case in Albany County. Petition of John Constable, surgeon, whose clientele complained to the Grand Jury about his small pox inoculations. Constable complains case is proceeding to slowly.
    - Petition to the Assembly, 1766 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Petition to appoint a Commissioner of roads in Manor of St. George. Filed under Zopher Garad, first name.
    - Commission of Lunacy of Sarah Ann Delaplaine, 1773 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Various fragments, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1730-1775 (bulk 1753-1774), and Undated, 1730-1775 and Undated
  - Subseries 1: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, 1759-1775 and Undated